Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Katrin and today we're talking all about cars in this intermediate level
我是Katrin，今天我们要在这节中级课程中聊聊汽车。
lesson.
课程。
That's right.
没错。
We have a little bit of problems with our car and we're going to talk about some possible
我们的车出了点小问题，我们要讨论一些可能的
solutions to these car problems we have.
解决方案。
So why don't we just listen to the dialogue today.
那我们直接听今天的对话吧。
We have no words on vocabulary preview so let's jump right into the dialogue and listen
我们没有词汇预览，所以直接进入对话，第一次
for the first time.
听。
Car trouble center, how may I help you?
汽车故障中心，有什么可以帮您的？
My car won't start.
我的车发动不了。
Stupid old car.
破旧的老车。
Hold on.
等等。
Before you kick your car, let's go through some possible problems.
在你踢车之前，我们先排查一下可能的问题。
Fine.
好吧。
Okay.
好的。
First of all, can you turn the key in the ignition?
首先，你能转动点火开关里的钥匙吗？
Yeah.
能。
I'm here with my friend and he thinks it may be the spark plug or the starter motor.
我和朋友在一起，他觉得可能是火花塞或启动马达的问题。
Those are possible problems, but tell me, when you turn the key, do you hear the starter
这些是可能的问题，但告诉我，当你转动钥匙时，你听到启动
motor crank?
马达转动的声音吗？
Yeah.
听到了。
It sounds like it usually does when I start the car, but nothing else happens.
听起来和我平时启动车时一样，但其他什么都没发生。
The engine won't start.
引擎启动不了。
Should I maybe press the accelerator?
我是不是该踩一下油门？
No.
不。
If you step on the accelerator pedal, you can flood the carburetor and your car will
如果你踩油门踏板，可能会让化油器溢油，你的车就
never start.
永远启动不了了。
So what do you think it is?
那你觉得是什么问题？
I know this may seem like a silly question, but does your car have gasoline?
我知道这问题可能有点傻，但你的车有汽油吗？
Um, yeah, right.
嗯，对哦。
I got the car started.
我把车发动起来了。
Thanks for your help.
谢谢你的帮助。
I told you to fill the tank.
我告诉过你要加满油箱。
Okay, so this dialogue reminds me a lot of a radio show in America called Car Talk.
好的，这段对话让我想起美国一个叫《汽车谈话》的广播节目。
And the hosts of the show, like Marco and I today, they talk about how to solve problems
节目的主持人，就像今天我和Marco一样，他们讨论如何解决问题，
and they ask you questions to find out what the problem is.
并问你问题来找出问题所在。
So it's a really helpful show, but let's take a look at some of the phrases and words that
所以这是个很有帮助的节目，但让我们看看你听到的一些短语和单词，
you heard so we can understand what exactly is going on here.
这样我们就能理解这里到底发生了什么。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, so today on Language Takeaway, we have five words and they're all very specific
好的，今天在语言要点中，我们有五个单词，它们都非常具体
to the car.
与汽车相关。
So why don't we start with the first word.
那我们先从第一个词开始。
It's a noun and we are talking about the ignition.
这是一个名词，我们在谈论点火开关。
Ignition.
点火开关。
The ignition is a part of the first step to starting a car.
点火开关是启动汽车的第一步的一部分。
Basically under the wheel of the car, the steering wheel, there is usually a silver
基本上在方向盘下面，通常有一个银色的
hole where you can put the key in.
孔，你可以把钥匙插进去。
This is the ignition.
这就是点火开关。
It starts the car.
它启动汽车。
Exactly.
没错。
So you put the key in the ignition and you can start the car.
所以你把钥匙插进点火开关，就可以启动汽车。
To start the car means to turn it on, to get it going.
启动汽车意味着把它打开，让它运转起来。
That's right.
没错。
And so ignition is the first step.
所以点火开关是第一步。
Starting the ignition.
启动点火开关。
Okay, so moving on to our next word.
好的，接下来看下一个词。
We have a word that's formed by two different parts.
我们有一个由两个不同部分组成的词。
A spark plug.
火花塞。
Spark plug.
So a spark plug is an electrical object.
火花塞是一个电气元件。
Basically this has to do with electricity and the way that the car gets energy.
基本上这与电有关，是汽车获取能量的方式。
So it's called a spark plug because it creates a spark, which is a brief burst of current.
它叫火花塞，因为它会产生火花，也就是短暂的电流爆发。
So this basically creates a small spark of electricity and this makes the gasoline ignite.
所以这基本上会产生一个小电火花，让汽油点燃。
So that's what makes the car go.
这就是让汽车动起来的原因。
Right.
对。
So energy is taken from the battery to start a small fire basically, which then starts
所以能量从电池中取出，基本上点燃一个小火，然后启动
the engine.
引擎。
Spark plug.
火花塞。
It's a very small but very important part of a car.
这是汽车中很小但非常重要的部件。
Very good.
非常好。
And moving on, we have the starter motor.
接下来，我们有启动马达。
Okay, to be very honest with you, I'm not a car person, so I'm not sure what the starter
好的，老实说，我不是汽车专家，所以我不太确定启动
motor is.
马达是什么。
So explain this to us, Marco.
所以给我们解释一下，Marco。
Okay.
好的。
So basically your car runs on gasoline.
基本上你的车靠汽油运行。
So you put your key into the ignition and you turn it.
所以你把钥匙插进点火开关，然后转动它。
This in turn sends energy to this little motor called the starter motor.
这反过来会把能量送到这个小马达，叫做启动马达。
And that basically gets the car going by means of an electrical current before the gasoline
它基本上通过电流让车动起来，在汽油
ignites.
点燃之前。
So it's like a little electrical motor that makes the spark plug ignite and causes some
所以它就像一个小电动机，让火花塞点火，并引起
of the mechanical parts like the pistons move within the car and then it turns on.
一些机械部件，比如活塞，在车内运动，然后车就启动了。
Okay.
好的。
So again, this is all about the beginning of when we turn the key in the ignition, what
所以再说一遍，这全是关于我们转动点火钥匙时开始的过程，
happens?
发生了什么？
This is a starter motor.
这是一个启动马达。
So once we've turned the car on, we've turned the key in the ignition, we have to worry
所以一旦我们启动了车，转动了点火钥匙，我们就得操心
about giving the car gas.
给车加油。
So we can control gas with the accelerator pedal.
我们可以用油门踏板来控制油量。
So by saying you want to give the car gas is you want to give it more energy, more power
所以说你想给车加油，就是你想给它更多能量、更多动力
or less energy, right?
或更少能量，对吧？
Right.
对。
So if I want to go very fast, I push my foot down on the accelerator and the further down
所以如果我想开得很快，我就用脚踩下油门，踩得越深，
it goes, the faster I move.
我开得越快。
Exactly.
没错。
So that's the accelerator.
那就是油门。
Now the opposite of making the car go would make the car stop and those are called?
现在，让车动的相反操作是让车停下，那叫什么？
Brakes.
刹车。
So on the left we have a brake pedal and on the right we have an accelerator pedal.
所以左边是刹车踏板，右边是油门踏板。
Very good.
很好。
Okay.
好的。
And talking about acceleration and gas, we have a very specific mechanical object and
说到加速和加油，我们有一个很具体的机械部件，
that's called a carburetor.
叫做化油器。
Okay.
好的。
Again, carburetor.
再说一遍，化油器。
I know that this is under the hood of my car, but I'm not sure what it does.
我知道它在我的引擎盖下面，但我不确定它是干什么的。
Let's talk about this.
我们来聊聊这个。
All right.
好的。
So it's not very common to have a carburetor anymore in new cars, but basically it's a
所以现在新车里化油器已经不常见了，但它基本上是一个
small device that controls the flow of gasoline from the gas tank to the engine.
小装置，控制汽油从油箱到发动机的流量。
And basically what it does, it creates, it makes the gasoline into a type of a very thin
它基本上做的是，它把汽油变成一种非常细的
mist and that's what cause, and that way, and that way the gasoline can ignite easier.
雾状，这样汽油就能更容易点燃。
So the further down you push your foot on the accelerator, the wider the little gap
所以你踩油门踩得越深，化油器上的那个小缝隙
or the hole will open on the carburetor and that way your car will go faster.
或孔就会开得越大，这样你的车就会开得更快。
All right.
好的。
Very good.
很好。
So that's all we've got for language takeaway today, but don't go anywhere.
这就是我们今天语言点学习的全部内容，但别走开。
We'll be back in a second with Fluency Builder.
我们马上回来，进入流利度训练。
Car trouble center.
汽车故障中心。
How may I help you?
有什么能帮您的？
My car won't start.
我的车发动不了。
Stupid old car.
破旧的老车。
Hold on.
等等。
Before you kick your car, let's go through some possible problems.
在你踢车之前，我们先过一遍可能的问题。
Fine.
好吧。
Okay.
好的。
First of all, can you turn the key in the ignition?
首先，你能转动点火钥匙吗？
Yeah.
能。
I'm here with my friend and he thinks it may be the spark plug or the starter motor.
我和我朋友在一起，他觉得可能是火花塞或启动马达的问题。
Those are possible problems, but tell me, when you turn the key, do you hear the starter
那些是可能的问题，但告诉我，当你转动钥匙时，你听到启动
motor crank?
马达转动的声音吗？
Yeah.
听到了。
It sounds like it usually does when I start the car, but nothing else happens.
听起来和我平时启动车时一样，但别的什么都没发生。
The engine won't start.
发动机启动不了。
Should I maybe press the accelerator?
我是不是该踩一下油门？
No.
不。
If you step on the accelerator pedal, you can flood the carburetor and your car will
如果你踩油门踏板，可能会淹了化油器，你的车就
never start.
永远启动不了了。
So what do you think it is?
那你觉得是什么问题？
I know this may seem like a silly question, but does your car have gasoline?
我知道这可能是个傻问题，但你的车有汽油吗？
Yeah.
有。
Right.
对。
I got the car started.
我把车启动了。
Thanks for your help.
谢谢你的帮助。
I told you to fill the tank.
我告诉过你把油箱加满。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now why don't we take a look at four key phrases that we have for you on Fluency Builder.
那么现在，我们来看看流利度训练中为你准备的四个关键短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
Okay, this first phrase.
好的，第一个短语。
So you heard the phrase at the beginning, car trouble center, but car trouble center,
你一开始听到了“汽车故障中心”这个短语，但“汽车故障中心”
that's maybe the name of a fake company that we use.
可能只是我们用的一个虚构公司名字。
But the phrase car trouble is very, very common.
但“汽车故障”这个短语非常非常常见。
So if you say I'm having car trouble or I had some car trouble, what does that mean?
所以如果你说“我遇到汽车故障了”或“我有点汽车故障”，那是什么意思？
That means my car broke.
那意思是我的车坏了。
Okay.
好的。
So you don't say my car broke.
所以你不会说“我的车坏了”。
This is one thing that can't break because normally you say I'm having trouble or I'm
这是不会坏的一件事，因为通常你会说“我遇到麻烦了”或“我
having car trouble because a part of my car is not working.
的车出了麻烦”，因为我的车某个部件不工作了。
Okay.
好的。
So instead of saying I'm having problems with my car or my car broke, you just say I had
所以，与其说“我的车有问题”或“我的车坏了”，你只需说“我遇到了
car trouble or I'm having car trouble.
车的问题”或“我正在遇到车的问题”。
That's right.
没错。
So this is a really good excuse for coming to work late.
所以这是上班迟到的一个很好的借口。
You can say, oh, I'm so sorry.
你可以说，哦，非常抱歉。
I was having car trouble this morning.
我今天早上遇到了车的问题。
Right.
对。
So any type of problems with your car can be considered car trouble.
所以任何与车有关的问题都可以被视为车的问题。
Flat tire, no battery, etc.
轮胎瘪了、没电了等等。
Okay.
好的。
Now moving on, we have a very interesting verb here.
现在继续，我们这里有一个非常有趣的动词。
We heard when the guy was talking about the starter motor, he said, do you hear the starter
我们听到那个人在谈论启动马达时说，你听到启动
motor crank?
马达转动的声音了吗？
Okay, to crank.
好的，转动。
So this is a very interesting verb.
所以这是一个非常有趣的动词。
It can also be a noun.
它也可以是一个名词。
It's a sound.
它是一种声音。
Okay.
好的。
It's a movement.
它是一种运动。
So when something turns around in a circle, maybe you think of a metal wheel.
所以当某物绕圈转动时，你可能会想到一个金属轮子。
That's a crank.
那就是曲柄。
So sometimes we talk about those old cars, you know, 1910s, 1920s, the first Ford cars,
所以有时我们谈论那些老式汽车，你知道，1910年代、1920年代，第一批福特汽车，
you had to crank them in the front.
你必须在前面摇动它们。
You had to actually turn with your hand a wheel to make the car start.
你必须用手转动一个轮子才能让车启动。
So this is a crank.
所以这就是曲柄。
Exactly.
正是。
You can hear this in your car.
你可以在你的车里听到这个声音。
Maybe if your car doesn't have gasoline, you hear the tick, tick, tick, tick, that's
也许如果你的车没油了，你会听到嘀、嘀、嘀、嘀的声音，那就是
the starter motor cranking.
启动马达在转动。
So it's going around in circles, trying to create energy.
所以它一圈圈地转，试图产生能量。
Exactly.
正是。
And now when the guy was talking about the accelerator and he was talking about the carburetor,
现在，当那个人谈论加速器和化油器时，
he said, no, don't step on that pedal because you can flood the carburetor.
他说，不，别踩那个踏板，因为你会淹了化油器。
So to flood.
所以是“淹”。
Okay.
好的。
To flood.
“淹”。
This is a verb.
这是一个动词。
Maybe you've heard the word flood before as a noun, but this means to fill something with
也许你以前听过“flood”这个词作为名词，但这里的意思是往某物里灌满
liquid, with gasoline, with water, with milk.
液体，比如汽油、水、牛奶。
So to flood something is to fill it up with a liquid.
所以“淹”某物就是把它灌满液体。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So you can flood a dam, for example, right?
所以你可以淹一个水坝，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
Or in this case, you can flood a carburetor, which means it won't work because it's all
或者在这个情况下，你可以淹一个化油器，这意味着它因为全湿了
wet.
而无法工作。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
And the last phrase that we have very handy when you're talking about cars is to fill
最后一个短语，在谈论汽车时非常实用，就是“加满
the tank.
油箱”。
Okay.
好的。
This is always a problem at my house because I hate to fill the tank.
这在我家一直是个问题，因为我讨厌加满油箱。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
Whenever my car's in the driveway and someone in my family asks if they can borrow it, I
每当我的车停在车道上，家里有人问我能不能借车时，我
say, yeah, sure.
就说，好的，当然。
And then obviously an hour later, they come back and say, why don't you ever fill the
然后显然一小时后，他们回来说，你为什么从来不把
tank?
油箱加满？
It's empty.
它是空的。
You have no gas.
你没油了。
I say, well, I hate to fill the car with gas.
我说，嗯，我讨厌给车加油。
And so I always have an empty tank.
所以我的油箱总是空的。
So I never fill the tank.
所以我从不加满油箱。
Okay.
好的。
So that's what it means to fill the tank is to have it full of gasoline.
所以“加满油箱”的意思就是让油箱装满汽油。
Right.
对。
To put gasoline into your gasoline tank.
把汽油加进你的汽油箱里。
Okay.
好的。
Very good.
非常好。
So we're going to go back and listen to the dialogue for the last time.
所以我们要回去最后一次听对话。
And we'll be back to talk a little bit more.
然后我们会回来再聊一会儿。
Car trouble center.
汽车故障中心。
How may I help you?
有什么可以帮您的？
My car won't start.
我的车发动不了。
Stupid old car.
破旧的老车。
Hold on.
等一下。
Before you kick your car, let's go through some possible problems.
在你踢你的车之前，我们先过一遍可能的问题。
Fine.
好吧。
Okay.
好的。
First of all, can you turn the key in the ignition?
首先，你能把钥匙插进点火开关里转一下吗？
Yeah.
嗯。
I'm here with my friend and he thinks it may be the spark plug or the starter motor.
我和我朋友在这儿，他觉得可能是火花塞或者启动马达的问题。
Those are possible problems.
那些是可能的原因。
But tell me, when you turn the key, do you hear the starter motor crank?
但告诉我，你转钥匙的时候，听到启动马达转动的声音了吗？
Yeah.
听到了。
It sounds like it usually does when I start the car, but nothing else happens.
听起来和我平时启动车时一样，但就是没别的反应。
The engine won't start.
引擎发动不起来。
Should I maybe press the accelerator?
我是不是该踩一下油门？
No.
别。
If you step on the accelerator pedal, you can flood the carburetor and your car will
如果你踩油门踏板，可能会把化油器淹了，那样你的车就
never start.
永远别想启动了。
So what do you think it is?
那你觉得是什么问题？
I know this may seem like a silly question, but does your car have gasoline?
我知道这问题可能有点傻，但你的车有油吗？
Yeah.
有。
Right.
对。
I got the car started.
我把车发动起来了。
Thanks for your help.
谢谢你的帮忙。
I told you to fill the tank.
我告诉过你把油箱加满。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So talking about cars and car trouble, I understand, for example, in some countries, when you're
说到车和车的问题，我了解到，比如在一些国家，当你
getting a driver's license, you're forced or obliged to learn a little bit of car mechanics.
考驾照的时候，你被迫或者必须学一点汽车机械知识。
You have to learn about the engine or how to change your tire and basic things like
你得学习发动机、怎么换轮胎，以及类似的基本
this.
东西。
That's a brilliant idea.
这个主意太棒了。
In America, you don't have to know how to fix your car.
在美国，你不需要知道怎么修车。
You have to know how to pay someone to fix your car.
你只需要知道怎么付钱让别人修车。
But basically, we only learn the rules of the road.
但基本上，我们只学道路规则。
So the signs and the basic rules.
就是标志和基本规则。
Really?
真的吗？
Yeah.
是啊。
But I think it would be very helpful to know how to fix a tire or how to change the oil
但我觉得知道怎么修轮胎或者怎么换
in your car.
机油会很有帮助。
I mean, is this a requirement in Ecuador?
我的意思是，这在厄瓜多尔是要求吗？
Yeah.
是的。
When you're getting your driver's permit, your driver's license, you have to take a
当你考取驾驶许可证、驾照的时候，你必须上一门
course which shows you the mechanics of the car, first aid course, and also basic road
课，教你汽车的机械原理、急救课程，还有基本的道路
rules and all that stuff.
规则之类的东西。
But basically, because it can be something very simple, like for example, they show you
但基本上，因为可能是一些很简单的东西，比如他们教你
where the battery is, where you can check the oil and basic things like this.
电池在哪里、怎么检查机油，以及类似的基本知识。
So maybe the little cable from the battery just came loose and that's why your car won't
所以也许电池的小电线松了，这就是你的车
start.
发动不起来的原因。
So instead of you waiting for two hours until somebody comes and picks you up or a tow truck,
这样你就不用等两个小时，直到有人来接你或者拖车来，
you can just check very briefly basic things that can maybe go wrong in your car and you
你可以简单检查一下车上可能出问题的基础部件，
can just go on your way.
然后就能继续上路了。
That's awesome.
太棒了。
I had my dad for that.
我有我老爸教我这个。
My dad said, I'm not going to have a little girl who doesn't know how to change a tire
我老爸说，我可不想有个连换轮胎
or who doesn't know how to check the oil level.
或者检查机油都不会的小女儿。
But not everybody has a parent who will teach them.
但不是每个人都有父母会教他们。
Right.
没错。
And it's very handy because, for example, you get a flat tire and sometimes cars can
而且这非常实用，因为比如你爆胎了，有时候车
be a little bit tricky.
会有点棘手。
The wheel nuts are sometimes covered by a plastic cover so you don't know how to take
轮毂螺母有时被塑料盖盖着，你不知道怎么
it off.
取下来。
There's a special tool for that.
有专门的工具。
Or the jack.
或者千斤顶。
Sometimes the jack is not the normal one that you have to pump up and down.
有时候千斤顶不是那种需要上下压的普通款。
It's a little one that you have to turn a lever and you have to do this.
而是那种需要转动杠杆的小型款，你得这样操作。
So it's very, very useful to know these things.
所以知道这些非常非常有用。
Absolutely.
绝对是的。
I'm curious to know if our listeners out there have experience with cars and car mechanics
我很好奇我们的听众有没有关于车和汽车机械的经验，
and if you have this rule, like Marco says they have in Ecuador, about learning about
以及你们那里有没有像Marco说的厄瓜多尔那样的规定，在
cars before you actually get your driver's license.
拿到驾照之前先学习汽车知识。
Let us know on our website, EnglishPod.com.
在我们的网站EnglishPod.com上告诉我们。
We hope to see you there.
希望在那里见到你们。
All right, guys.
好了，各位。
And remember, congrats to all of our listeners because you are one more person on this Sherwood
记住，恭喜我们所有的听众，因为你们是这条舍伍德
line.
线上的又一个人。